ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/168
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Research Department Records
1890-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/168
13.5 cubic feet
13.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, records (documents), pamphlets.
These files contain books, journals, reports, pamphlets, advertisements, and correspondence of the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Also included are correspondence of Lazare Teper, organizational material from local unions all over the United States, reports and writings by Research Department staff (including analyses of strikes between 1940 and 1945), files on the Cone Mills and S. Lichtenberg campaigns, as well as documents collected by the department. Among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960.
5512000
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
J. Woodward, December 12, 2003
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Formed in 1937, the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU) supported the administrative operations of the Union and coordinated the ILGWU's investigative operations. It provided union leaders with information on wages, working conditions, economic conditions, and other matters in the women's garment industry; analyzed information for the union; and monitored developments in the industry.
In addition to providing research for union leadership, Research Department staff prepared materials for Congressional testimony, presented cases on behalf of local unions to the War Labor Board, and worked to administer the Fair Labor Standards Act. At times, the director of the Research Department represented the ILGWU in national forums.
The Department also maintained an extensive library, collecting and housing documents from Union administrative staff that were deemed substantive and of lasting value to the Union, whether produced internally or externally. The information gathered by the Department was of particular value during labor disputes and contract negotiations.
Lazare Teper was the founding director of the ILGWU's Research Department, working in that position from 1937 to 1980. Born in Russia sometime between 1906 and 1908, Teper later studied at the University of Paris and earned his doctorate at Johns Hopkins University. He died in New York City in 1985.
Scope and Contents
The Research Department records reflect the department's varied functions, documenting its role in gathering and analyzing information for international and local union leadership, representing the union before government and labor organizations, and gathering materials of research, and oftentimes historical, value. Some segments of the records focus on one aspect of the department's work, and others include documentation across the department's functions.
Research Department director Lazare Teper's papers, for example, include files relating to the Wage Stabilization Board (5780/105). The department also maintained records focused on the National Coat and Suit Industry Board (statements of receipts and disbursements, label division reports, meetings minutes, bulletins to members, and other reports and resolutions), as well as some related legal files (5780/123). Also among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960. (5780/168)
Parts of the Research Department records consist primarily of collected documents from ILGWU affiliates. In this way, they resemble and, in some instances, complement the parts of the Archives Department Records (5780/121, 5780/121 PUBS), records generated by local unions (Series III), and the general collection of ILGWU publications (5780 PUBS). Research Department records of this kind contain records of predecessor unions to the ILGWU and ILGWU local union records (5780/045), or the annual report, "Conditions in the Women's Clothing Industry" (5780/078).
Other parts of the Research Department records document all of the department's functions. These records include financial and administrative reports, meeting minutes, and correspondence (5780/056, 5780/209), collected printed material (5780/168), and ILGWU statements on issues related to the garment industry (5780/209).
The files of this collection contain books, journals, reports, pamphlets, advertisements, and correspondence of the Research Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Also included are correspondence of Lazare Teper, organizational material from local unions all over the United States, reports and writings by Research Department staff (including analyses of strikes between 1940 and 1945), files on the Cone Mills and S. Lichtenberg campaigns, as well as documents collected by the department. Among the documents collected by the Research Department are the New York Coat and Suit Industry Reports between 1934 and 1960.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/045: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/056: ILGWU Research Department Collected Documents 5780/078: ILGWU Research Department Reports 5780/105: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/123: ILGWU Research Department Records 5780/209: ILGWU Research Department Records
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Women's clothing industry--New York (State)--New York.; Child labor--United States.; Child labor--New York (State)--New York.; Minimum wage--United States.; Minimum wage--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)--New York.; Clothing workers--United States.; Clothing workers--New York (State)--New York.; Industrial relations--United States.; Industrial relations--New York (State)--New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.
5512000
- Leslie Frank, My Experience as a Sweater, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  July 26, 1890
  - Item 1: Frank Leslie's Illustrated Newspaper, Publication (Box 1, Folder 1)
    July 26, 1890. Item is in English.
- Leslie Frank - Leslie's Illustrated Weekly: The Sweating Shops of New York, 1894; Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
  August 23, 1894
  - Item 1: Leslie's Illustrated Weekly, Publication (Box 1, Folder 2)
    August 23, 1894. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Investigation of the Complaint of the National Skirt and Sportswear Assn. Against Local 105, 1953; Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Investigation of the complaint of the National Skirt and Sportswear Assn. against Local 105., Publication (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Item is in English.
- Tuckman, Jacob - Survey of the members of the Joint Board of Cloakmakers, I.L.G.W.U., Prior to Retirement and After Retirement, 1951; Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: [Survey of the members of the Joint Board of Cloakmakers, I.L.G.W.U., prior to retirement and after retirement.], Publication (Box 1, Folder 4)
    By Tuckman, Jacob. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Survey of Shops that have Gone Out of Business or Reduced Operations, 1971; Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Survey of shops that have gone out of business or reduced operations, Publication (Box 1, Folder 5)
- I.L.G.W.U. Joint Board, Dress and Waistmakers' Union, New York City Research Department, Investigation into the Price Settlement System, 1937; Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Joint Board, Dress and Waistmakers' Union, N.Y.C. Research Department: Investigation into the price settlement system, Publication (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Fall 1939. Item is in English.
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Spring 1940. Item is in English.
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Spring 1939. Item is in English.
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Fall 1938. Item is in English.
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1940; Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Fall 1940. Item is in English.
- Price Analysis: Statistical Files, 1941; Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Price Analysis, Publication (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Fall 1941. Item is in English.
- Statistical Files: Report and Analysis of Price Rate Settlements for Dress Industry, 1936-1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Report and Analysis of Piece Rate Settlements for Dress Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 13)
    April 1936 - December 1938. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Joint Board, Dress and Waistmaker's Union, N.Y.C. Research Department Report and Analysis of Price Rate Settlements for Dress Industry, 1943- 1945; Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: I.L.G.W.U. Joint Boad, Dress and Waistmakers' union N.Y.C. Research Dept., Report and Analysis of Piece Rate Settlements for Dress Industry, Publication (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Fall 1943 - Spring 1945. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Joint Board, Dress and Waistmaker's Union, N.Y.C. Research Dept. Weekly Reports on Number of Styles Settled, 1936-1939; Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: I.L.G.W.U. Joint Board, Dress and Waistmakers' Union N.Y.C. Research Department, Weekly Reports On Number Of Styles Settled, Publication (Box 1, Folder 15)
    July 10, 1936- October 8, 1939. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau of New York, Coat and Suit Industry, 1955; Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Labor Bureau New York Coat and Suit Industry Report 1955 Spring Season, Publication (Box 1, Folder 16)
    May 5, 1955. Item is in English.
- Daniels, Wilbur. Statement on Behalf of the I.L.G.W.U. on the New York State Department of Labor Before the New York State Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions, 1948; Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Statement on behalf of the I.L.G.W.U. on the New York State Department of Labor before the New York State Joint Legilative Committee on Industrial and Labor conditions, Publication (Box 1, Folder 17)
    By Wilbur Daniels. Item is in English.
- New York State Dept. of Labor Division of Research and Statistics, Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research & Statistics; Vol. II - Exhibits, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Panel appraising work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Volume II. Exhibits, Publication (Box 1, Folder 18)
- New York State Dept. of Labor Division of Research and Statistics, Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol. II - Exhibits, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol. II - Exhibits, Publication (Box 1, Folder 19)
- New York State Dept. of Labor Division of Research and Statistics, Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol. II - Exhibit, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol II - Exhibit, Publication (Box 1, Folder 20)
- New York State Dept. of Labor Division of Research and Statistics, Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol. I - Correspondence & Drafts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Panel appraising work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol I - Correspondence and Drafts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 21)
- New York State Dept. of Labor Division of Research and Statistics, Panel Appraising Work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol. I - Correspondence & Drafts, 1949; Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Panel appraising work of the Bureau of Research and Statistics; Vol I - Correspondence and Drafts, Publication (Box 1, Folder 22)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Analysis of Strikes, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 23)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Analysis of Strikes, 1938; Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 1, Folder 24)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1940; Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 2: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 1)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1940; Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 2)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1942; Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 3)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1943; Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 4)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1944; Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 5)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department Analysis of Strikes, 1945; Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Analysis of Strikes, Publication (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1958 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 7)
    November 18, 1958. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1959 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 8)
    October 19, 1959. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1957 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 9)
    November 11, 1957. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1958 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 10)
    August 18, 1958. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1956 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 11)
    June 25, 1956. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1955 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 12)
    October 19, 1955. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1955 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1953 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 14)
    November 11, 1953. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1952 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 15)
    November 17, 1952. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, Spring 1960 Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 16)
    March 29, 1960. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, Fall 1960 Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 17)
    October 20, 1960. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1954 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 18)
    January 3, 1955. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1959 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 19)
    April 6, 1959. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1954 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 20)
    January 13, 1955. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau New York, Coat & Suit Industry Report, 1953 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 21)
    May 18, 1953. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Contracts Awarded by the War Department, Bulletin, 1943-1944; Publication (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Contracts Awarded During Last Week, Publication (Box 2, Folder 22)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Contracts Awarded by the War Department, Bulletin, 1944-1945; Publication (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Contracts Awarded by the Department, Publication (Box 2, Folder 23)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Women's Garment Industry & Military, Work, 1917-1918; Publication (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Women's Garment Industry and Military Work, Publication (Box 2, Folder 24)
    April 1917 to November 1918. Item is in English.
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Selected Correspondence Pertaining to Government Contracts, 1942-1950; Publication (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Selected Correspondence Pertaining to Government Contracts, Publication (Box 2, Folder 25)
- I.L.G.W.U. Research Department, Selected Correspondence Pertaining to Government Contracts, 1951-1952; Publication (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Selected Correspondence Pertaining to Government Contracts, Publication (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1948 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 27)
    April 5, 1948. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1948 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry Report, Publication (Box 2, Folder 28)
    October 21, 1948. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1949 Spring Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry, Publication (Box 2, Folder 29)
    March 29, 1949. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1949 Fall Season, Publication (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry Report, Publication (Box 2, Folder 30)
    November 22, 1949. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1936 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: New York coat and suit industry. Report: 1936 spring season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1936 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: New York coat and suit industry. Report: 1936 fall season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & suit Industry, Report: 1937 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: New York coat and suit industry. Report: 1937 spring season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry Report: 1937 Fall Season & 1938 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: New York coat and suit industry. Report: 1927 fall season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry: 1938 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: New York coat and suit industry. Report: 1938 fall season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report 1939 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
  August 12, 1939
  - Item 1: New York Coat and Suit Industry. Report. 1939 Spring season., Publication (Box 3, Folder 6)
    April 12, 1939. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1939 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1939 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 7)
    October 24, 1939. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1934 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Coat and suit industry, New York City. Report. 1934 fall season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1935 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Coat and suit industry, New York City Report. 1935 spring season., Publication (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1935 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Coat and suit industry, New York City. Report: 1935 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1943 Spring Season, 1942; Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1942 Spring Season, 1942 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 11)
    April 14, 1942. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1942 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1942 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 12)
    October 27, 1942. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1943 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1943 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1943 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1943 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1944 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1944 Spring Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 15)
    April 1, 1944. Item is in English.
- Labor Bureau, New York Coat & Suit Industry, Report: 1944 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Coat and Suit Industry. Report: 1944 Fall Season, Publication (Box 3, Folder 16)